
== Eclipse RAP

=== Introduction
		
			Eclipse RAP is a Eclipse based platform for Ajax web
			applications
			which provides part of the API of
			Eclipse RCP. Eclipse
			RAP
			allows to use Eclipse RCP paradigm for developing
			Ajax
			web-applications.
		
		
			RAP is based on the OSGi implementation Equinox. It is possible
			to run Eclipse RAP
			applications via the OSGi servlet
			bridge in a
			servlet container, e.g.
			Apache Tomcat
			or Jetty.
		
		Eclipse RAP supports extension points, views, perspectives,
			selection service,
			commands, handlers, editors and databinding.
		
		 Eclipse archives this by providing its own implementations for
			SWT, JFace and the Workbench. Eclipse RAP replaces SWT
			with RWT (RAP
			widget toolkit)
			layer. This toolkit is based on the qooxdoo Ajax
			library. RWT is a distributed system; every RWT widget has a client
			and a server part. These part communicate via Ajax.
		
		
			During development Eclipse RAP applications run in the embedded
			web server Jetty which is part of the
			Eclipse RAP
			development tooling.
		

	

=== Differences to Eclipse RCP
		
			Eclipse RAP does not provide all the possibilities
			Eclipse RCP.
			For example Eclipse RAP has no
			Graphics Context which can be
			used in
			SWT to draw directly onto the
			SWT widgets.
		
		 Each Eclipse RAP releases provides more functionality so that
			the differences between Eclipse RCP and Eclipse RAP are getting
			smaller every release.
		
	


=== Workspace and Target Platform
		 Eclipse RAP have its own target platform. A target platform
			contains the artifacts, e.g., plug-ins, against which the Eclipse
			plug-ins are compiled. For example
			Eclipse RAP does not rely
			on SWT but
			on RWT therefore the target platform must provide these.
		
		 Typically you should create a new workspace for your Eclipse
			RAP
			projects. As you
			have to change the target
			platform to
			compile
			against
			Eclipse RAP your
			existing projects may not
			work with the RAP
			target platform and may show syntax errors.
		
	
