== Optional Exercise: Using the model spy

=== Target
		
			To test the application model dynamics, integrate the model spy
			and its dependencies into the
			run
			configuration of
			your
			application.
		

		<warning>
			Do not modify your product configuration file for this
				exercise.
				You should not
				include the model spy in your
				exported
				application as
				it
				is only a test and debug tool. It is
				not intended to
				be used by end
				users.
			
		</warning>

		NOTE:
			The model spy is a debug tool and not intended to be used in a
				productive application. So it might happen that
				this exercise does
				not
				work, or that you see additional exceptions in your log file,
				caused by the tool.
			
		</note>
	

=== Add the spies to your target platform
		
			Add the model spies to your target platform. See
			tutorial_installation_e4spiesofficial">e4 spies
			for the update site.
		

	

=== Adding the model spy to your runtime configuration
		
			Open the run configuration of your product via the
			menu:Run[Run Configurations...]
			menu entry and
			add the
			`org.eclipse.e4.tools.model.spy`
			plug-in and its dependencies to it.
		
		
image::adding_liveeditor08.png[Adding the live editor to a run configuration,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
			If you use the filter you have to remove it before the
			_Add Required Plug-ins_
			becomes active again.
		


		
image::adding_liveeditor10.png[Adding the live editor to a run configuration,pdfwidth=60%]
		


		
			Press the
			_Validate_
			button to ensure that all dependencies are included.
		

	

=== Use the model spy

		
			After you have added the new plug-ins to your run
			configuration press the
			_Run_
			button in the run configuration you just added.
		
		<warning>
			Do not start the application now via the product. Starting via
				the product resets your changes in the runtime
				configuration.
			
		</warning>

		
			Start your application and use the
			kbd:[Shift+Alt+F9]
			shortcut to
			open the model spy.
		

		<warning>
			The code of the model spy adds this key binding to your
				application by modifying your application model at
				runtime. If you
				already
				defined key bindings this process
				might fail.
			
		</warning>

		Use the model spy to change the runtime application model. For
			example, add a part (with a label) or
			change the
			size of the
			window. All
			changes should become immediately
			visible
			(except new menu entries, these
			changes are not updated
			automatically due to a bug).
		
	


=== Cleanup - remove model spy from your run configuration
		
		After testing with the tool enabled, start your application
			again
			from your product configuration file to remove
			the live model
			editor
			plug-in from your run configuration.
		
		<warning>
			If you leave the model spy included in your run configuration, it might
				cause side effects, e.g., in the past
				it
				created
				exceptions if
				key
				bindings were present in the application.
			
		</warning>
	
