
== Eclipse preference settings

=== What are preferences?
		
		
			The behavior of the Eclipse IDE can be controlled via key value pairs
			stores as
			_preference_
			settings. Each Eclipse software component can define such perferences
			and use the values to configure itself. This allows you for example
			to configure how long the Eclipse waits before the code completion
			or if the import statements in your source code should be
			automatically adjusted if you save your source code.
		
		Which preferences are key values stored on the file system, the
			Eclipse IDE allows the user to configure most of these values via the
			preference dialog.
		
	

=== Opening the preference dialog
		

			Select
			menu:Window[Preferences]
			to open the preference dialog. You can use the filter box
			to
			search for
			specific settings.
		

		
image::preferencesettings17.png"
						scale="40[Preference settings,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		Correctly configuring Eclipse to your needs can largely improve
			your productivity. Most of these preference
			settings
			are specific to
			your workspace but some are also valid for all workspaces.
		
	


=== Configuring the preference values via the
			plugin_customization.ini file
		
			You can specify default values for preferences via a file which is
			typically called
			_plugin_customization.ini_
			.
		
		
			In this file you enter default values for preference settings.
			For
			example, the following will setup a default type filter for the
			`java.awt`
			and
			`javax.swing`
			package.
		

		
			<programlisting language="java">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="../examples/preferences/plugin_customization.ini" />
			</programlisting>
		
		
			You link to this file via your
			_eclipse.ini_
			file in your Eclipse
			installation directory.
		
		

			The following example
			_eclipse.ini_
			links to the file and it
			assumes
			that you created the
			_plugin_customization.ini_
			file in the Eclipse installation directory.
		
		
			<programlisting language="text">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="../examples/preferences/eclipse.ini" />
			</programlisting>
		

	

=== Identifying preference setting values
		
			To identify a key for a certain preference setting you can export
			existing preference settings via the following approach.

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					start a new workspace
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					change the preference
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					export all
						preferences
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					search the key in the exported file
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
		<note>
			
				You need
				to remove the scope (e.g., /instance/) before
				copying
				it into
				the
				_plugin_customization.ini_
				file.
			
		</note>
	
