== Contributing to the Eclipse open source project

=== Code contributing
		
			As the Eclipse project is an open source project, it is possible
			to get the source code, modify it and provide
			the change back to the
			project. Most Eclipse projects use a code review process based on the
			Gerrit code review system.
			Some Eclipse projects also use Github for code contributions.
		
		
			Contributing to an Eclipse project has the benefit of getting
			feedback directly from the core developers. It also
			allows developers
			and organizations to fix bugs which affect them and to drive the
			project into a desired direction.
		
		While there are other ways of contributing to an Eclipse project, e.g., via updating the project documentation,
			this $book focuses on the process of contributing code to an Eclipse project.
		
	

=== User interface guidelines
		
		
			Eclipse has a description for its user interface guidelines. These
			can be found under the following url:
			https://wiki.eclipse.org/User_Interface_Guidelines">Wiki about UI guidelines
			.
		
		
			It is not expected that you read this guide completely, but in
			case you
			want
			to check what the Eclipse way of doing
			things is, you can
			have a
			look
			at this (old but still valid) description.
		
	

=== Users, Contributors and Committers
		
		

		The development of the individual Eclipse projects is done by
			the
			Eclipse developers - companies and individuals
			alike
			- which
			develop
			the code.
		
		
			The Eclipse project distinguishes between the following group of
			people:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					
						Eclipse User - Using at least one product, e.g., a
						_JAR_
						file, of the Eclipse project. Eclipse users consume the software
						created by the Eclipse
						developers. Users also
						report bugs and issue feature requests in Eclipse projects they are using.
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					
						Contributors are individuals who contribute code, fixes, tests, documentation, or other work that is part of
						the project.
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					
						Committers have write access to the project's resources (source code repository, bug tracking system,
						website, build server, downloads, etc.) and are expected to influence the project's development.
					
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
		Everyone has read access to the code repositories hosted at
			eclipse.org.
		

	
	

        <title>Relevant Eclipse projects
        Eclipse hosts multiple projects but several projects are critical for the development of the Eclipse IDE and RCP
            applications. These are described here.
        
            <title>The Eclipse Platform project
            <indexterm>
                <primary>Platform project</primary>
            </indexterm>
            
                The
                _Eclipse Platform_
                project provides the core frameworks and
                services upon which all
                Eclipse based applications are created. It also
                provides the runtime
                in which
                Eclipse components are loaded, integrated, and
                executed. The
                primary purpose of
                the
                _Eclipse Platform_
                project is to enable
                other developers
                to easily
                build and deliver
                integrated tools and applications.
            
        

        
            <title>The Eclipse Plug-in Development Environment (PDE)
            <indexterm>
                <primary>PDE</primary>
            </indexterm>
            <indexterm>
                <primary>Plug-in Development Environment</primary>
            </indexterm>
            The Eclipse Plug-in Development Environment (PDE) project
                provides wizards for creating Eclipse RCP applications
                and plug-ins, editors and other tools to develop
                Eclipse
                plug-ins.
            
        
        
            <title>The Eclipse e4 project
            <indexterm>
                <primary>e4 project</primary>
            </indexterm>
            
                _Eclipse e4_
                is the name used for the
                _Eclipse Platform_
                incubator project. This
                incubator
                is used for exploratory projects
                relating to improving the
                Eclipse
                Platform.
            
            

                The
                e4 project includes several technology evaluations.
                Some of
                these
                evaluations have
                been ported
                back to
                the core Eclipse
                framework.
                All
                functionalities described
                in
                this
                document are
                part of the
                official
                Eclipse
                release,
                except
                the
                _Eclipse e4 tooling_
                project.
            

            
                The
                _Eclipse e4 tooling_
                project
                provides tools for developing
                Eclipse 4 applications. They are very
                useful, but have not yet been added
                to
                the
                Eclipse platform project.
            
        

    
	

