<section role="wrapper">
	<title>Finding information about an Eclipse project
	<section>
=== The Eclipse project page
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Project pages</primary>
		</indexterm>
		
			Additional information about a project can be found under its
			https://projects.eclipse.org/">Eclipse project page
			. This includes information about future developments plans,
			documentation, wiki pages, developer mailing lists and
			the project
			charter.
		
		
			The following screenshot depicts the website for the JDT UI
			project. This project page can be found under
			https://projects.eclipse.org/projects/eclipse.jdt.ui">JDT UI project page
			.
		
		
image::jdtuieclipseprojectpage10.png[Eclipse top-level project homepage,pdfwidth=60%]
		
	


[[versioncontrolprojects1">
=== Finding the Git repositories for an Eclipse project
		
			Eclipse lists
			all
			project repositories under their project
			page. This page can be found via the main
			https://projects.eclipse.org/">Eclipse projects page
			.
		
		
			Use this page to search for an Eclipse project.
			If you click on the
			_Learn more_
			in one of the search results you are taken to the project homepage. Click on the
			_Developer resources_
			tab to see all Git repositories of the project.
		
	
[[versioncontrolprojects2">
=== Example: Finding the Git repositories for the Eclipse Platform UI project
		
			The Eclipse platform UI project is responsible for the user interface, runtime and user assistant components of
			the
			Eclipse platform. In this example search for "Platform UI".
		

		
image::eclipsegitrepos10.png" scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Eclipse Platform UI search result,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
			Click on the
			_Learn more_
			link and select the
			_Developer resources_
			tab.
		
		
image::eclipsegitrepos20.png[Eclipse Platform UI developer resources`,pdfwidth=60%]
		

	

[[eclipseplatform_dashboard">
=== The Eclipse dashboard
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Dashboard</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Eclipse dashboard</primary>
		</indexterm>
		
			At the time of this writing the Eclipse foundation is setting up
			a
			new
			http://dashboard.eclipse.org/">dashboard
			.
		
		
			For example
			http://dashboard.eclipse.org/its-contributors.html">
			gives an overview of Eclipse contributions. The dashboard allows
			you
			to drill down as depicted in the following
			screenshot.
		
		<note>
			
				The URL and appearance may still change. See
				https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=405792">Bug 405792
				for details.
			
		</note>
		
image::eclipsedash10.png" scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Project members dash,pdfwidth=60%]
		

		You can select in the top the sub-project to see. For example
			the reporting for the Eclipse project is depicted
			in the following
			screenshot.
		

		
image::eclipsedash20.png" scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Eclipse project dashboard,pdfwidth=60%]
		
	
