
== Clone the selected Eclipse Git repository

=== Finding the correct Git repository
		Ensure you are logged into the Gerrit server webpage. This will enable you to use SSH or
			HTTPS for cloning the
			repository.
		
		
			Go to the
			https://git.eclipse.org/r/">Gerrit Eclipse homepage
			and select the
			menu:Projects[List]
			menu entry. This opens the
			https://git.eclipse.org/r/#/admin/projects/">Project search page
			. Afterwards search for the project you want to contribute to. In our example we want to contribute to the
			platform.ui project.
		
		
image::gerrit_getcloneurl10.png[Get URL to clone a Gerrit project,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
			Select the correct project. This opens a new webpage.
			This page contains links for cloning the Git
			repository. The
			selection
			for HTTPS is
			depicted in the
			following
			screenshot. Please note that the URL for you is different, as it
			contains your user name.
		
		
image::gerrit_getcloneurl30.png[Get URL to clone a Gerrit project,pdfwidth=60%]
		

	

=== Clone the repository via the Eclipse IDE
		
			To clone, select
			menu:File[Import... > Git > Projects from Git > Clone URI]
			.
		

		
image::gerrit_getcloneurl40.png[Get URL to clone a Gerrit project,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
image::gerrit_getcloneurl50.png[Get URL to clone a Gerrit project,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		Enter the URL from the Gerrit webpage in the first line of the wizard. The Eclipse Git tooling removes "git
			clone" from the clone URI automatically.
		
		
			Note that the URL automatically includes your user name. This makes
			it
			easier to push a change to the Eclipse
			Gerrit
			review
			system. If you clone the repository using the Eclipse Git functionality, your local repository is already
			configured to push changes to Gerrit, no additional setup step is required. You can also clone anonymously via
			_Anonymous HTTP_
			, if you just want to play with
			the source code locally and do not intend to
			contribute changes. The following
			screenshot shows this selection, please the depicted user name with yours.
		
		
image::gerrit_getcloneurl60.png[Get URL to clone a Gerrit project,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
			On the next wizard page you can choose to clone all branches or only the master branch. Finish this wizard by
			selecting the
			_Next_
			button
			until you the option
			_Finish_
			option becomes available. You end up with the projects from the repository imported into your workspace.
		

		NOTE:
			
				In case you cloned a Git repository without using the
				Gerrit URL or not via Eclipse Git you
				have to adjust the
				push URL.
				See
				<xref linkend="eclipsegerritcontribution_adjustpush" />
				for a description how to do that.
			

		</note>

	

