<section id="eclipsegerritcontribgution_pushsetup" role="wrapper">
	<title>Exercise: make a change and push a review</title>
	<section id="eclipsegerritcontribution_codechange">
		<title>Make a code change</title>
		<para>
			Find a very simple change for your first contribution. For
			example fix a typo or a compiler warning. Eclipse
			projects
			frequently tag bugs with the keyword
			<wordasword>bugday</wordasword>
			or
			<wordasword>helpwanted</wordasword>
			, these are candidates for initial contributions.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="eclipsegerritcontribution_push">
		<title>Push to the Gerrit review system</title>
		<para>
			Use the
			<guilabel>Git Staging</guilabel>
			view to commit your change and to push it to the Gerrit review server.
		</para>
		<para>
			You
			need to sign off every commit. The Git functionality in Eclipse
			simplifies that via the
			sign-off
			push button. The
			<guilabel>Add Change-Id</guilabel>
			push button allows you to include a Change-Id entry to the commit
			message. Both buttons are highlighted in the
			following screenshot.
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/eclipsegerritcontribution20.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Eclipse Signed-off-by</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				The Change-ID entry is initially set to "Change-Id:
				I0000000000000000000000000000000000000000". During the
				commit, this
				is replaced with an ID generated by the Git tooling. Like other
				Git
				IDs it is a SHA1 over the content it
				captures and the letter 'I'
				is
				added a prefix to make it obvious that it is a Gerrit Change-Id and
				not
				a
				Git commit ID.
			</para>
		</note>
		<warning>
			<para>
				To get picked up by Gerrit, the
				<wordasword>Change-Id</wordasword>
				must be in the last paragraph together with the other footers.
				To
				avoid problems do not separate it from the
				<wordasword>Signed-off-by</wordasword>
				message
				with a new-line character.
			</para>
		</warning>
	</section>
	<section id="eclipsegerritcontribution_reviewupdating">
		<title>Updating the Gerrit review</title>
		<para>
			You may get review comments asking to improve the Gerrit change. Or you find a better way of doing the change.
			You can update an existing Gerrit review by using the same Change-Id for another commit. The easiest way of doing
			this is to amend the last commit and push this commit again to Gerrit.
		</para>
		<para>
			Since the amended commit contains
			the same Change-Id as the
			initial commit, Gerrit knows that you want to
			update
			this change with
			the new commit. Also in your local Git
			repository commit amend
			replaces the previous commit in your
			local history (and keep
			the same
			parent commit).
		</para>
	</section>


</section>
