
== Create bindings

=== Using the ISideEffect API 

		
			Eclipse 4.6 introduces the
			`ISideEffect`
			databinding API. It allows you to run code whenever one or more
			observables change. An ISideEffect is a lot like a
			listener except
			that it doesn't need to be attached to anything. Instead, it reacts
			automatically to changes in the
			tracked properties.
		
		

			For example, the
			following code updates the label with the value of the user name every time the user name
			changes.
		
		
[source,java]
----
include::res/sideeffect/example.txt[]
----
		


		
			ISideEffects can react to changes in multiple observables, and will
			avoid performing excessive updates,
			if the
			observables fire many change events in a short period of time.
		
		
			You can use the ISideEffectFactory to create several ISideEffect instances that share the same life cycle.
			For
			example, all ISideEffect instances that are created by the ISideEffectFactory obtained from the
			WidgetSideEffects#createFactory(Widget disposableWidget) method are automatically disposed once the corresponding
			widget is disposed.
		
		
[source,java]
----
include::res/sideeffect/Reuse.txt[]
----
		


	

=== Connecting properties with the DataBindingContext
		
		
			The
			`DataBindingContext`
			class
			provides the functionality to connect
			`IObservableValue`
			objects.
		

		
			Via the
			`DataBindingContext.bindValue()`
			method two
			`IObservableValue`
			objects are connected. The first parameter is the target and the
			second is the
			model. During the initial binding the
			value from the
			model
			is copied to the target. The initial copying from model to target is useful for the
			initial
			synchronization. For example if you have an
			attribute of a
			`Person`
			p
			object and the text attribute of a
			`Text`
			txtName widget, you typically want to copy the value from p to
			txtName at the beginning.
		

		
[source,java]
----
include::res/snippets/dbc.java[]
----
		
		
			You can also observe nested model properties, e.g.,
			attributes of classes which are contained in another class.
			The
			following code
			demonstrates how to access the
			<property>country</property>
			property in the
			<property>address</property>
			field of the object
			<property>person</property>
			.
		

		
[source,java]
----
include::res/snippets/nested.java[]
----
		

	


=== Observing map properties

		
			You can also observe entries of a map via an
			`IObservableMap`
			with the
			`Observables.observeMapEntry()`
			method. This allows you to control the point in time when you want to update or use the values from the map.
		
		
[source,java]
----
include::res/snippets/ObservableMapEntry.java[]
----
		
	


