== Git integration into the Package and the Project Explorer
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Eclipse Git</primary>
		<secondary>Package Explorer integration
		</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	
		The
		_Package Explorer_
		view
		shows indicators on the files to show their status. The most
		important
		icon decorators are depicted in the following screenshot.
	

	
image::jdt_packageexplorer_icondecu10.png"
					scale="60" />
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Icon decorator</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	
	
		The file name describes the state of the file from the following
		table:

.Table Title
|===

	=== Git label decorations
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' colwidth="1*" />
				<colspec colname='c2' colwidth="3*" />
				
					
|State
|Description
					
				
				
					
|tracked
|File is committed to the Git repository and has not
							changed.
						
					
					
|untracked
|File is neither staged nor committed. 
					
					
|ignored
|File is flagged to be ignored by Git operations. 
					
					
|dirty
|File has changed since the last commit.
					


					
|staged
|
							Changes in the file will be included in the next
							commit.
						
					
					
|partially-staged
|
							The resource has changes which are added
							to the index and
							additional unstaged changes in the working tree
						
					
					
|added
|
							Staged but not yet committed, i.e. snapshot
							of this
							file has been
							stored in the git database. This status is the same
							as the
							_staged_
							status,
							but the file wasn't under Git version control before.
						
					

					
|removed
|The resource is staged for removal from the Git repository.
						
					
					
|conflict
|A merge conflict exists for the file. 
					
				
			
		|===

	
	A combination of the staged and dirty status means: some parts
		of
		the changed
		file have been staged while some are still unstaged.
		This
		can
		happen if
		you stage a file and then again modify the file
		before
		creating the
		next commit. You can also change the staged parts
		using
		the compare
		editor opened by double clicking files in the staging
		view.
	
	
		On a project level the explorer
		view
		adds the
		information which Git
		repository is
		used to the
		project name. It also adds
		the number of
		commits that are
		different between
		local and remote
		tracking branch.
		This
		way you can
		quickly see if your
		local branch is
		ahead or behind the
		remote branch
		it is tracking.
	

	
image::jdt_packageexplorer_icondecu20.png"
					scale="60" />
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Git icon decorator in the Package Explorer</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	

