
	<title>Writing good commit messages
[[commitmessages_content">
=== Importance of Git commit messages
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Commit message</primary>
		</indexterm>
		
			A
			_commit_
			adds a new version to the repository. This version is described by a
			_commit message_
			.
		
		
			The
			_commit message_
			describes the changes recorded in a commit and helps the user to
			understand the history of the files contained in a Git repository.
		
		
			A commit
			message should therefore be descriptive and informative
			without repeating the
			code changes.
		
	
[[commitmessages_guideline">
=== Guidelines for useful commit messages
		A commit message should have a header and a body. The header
			should be less than 50 characters and the body should wrap its text
			at 72 so that the commit message is displayed well on the command
			line or in graphical tools displaying the history. The body should be
			separated from the header by an empty line.
		
		The body should
			mainly describe the reason why the change was
			made. The changes in the file can be reviewed with the help of Git.
		
		The commit message should be in present tense, e.g., "Adds better
			error handling" instead of "Added better error handling".
		
		
			The last paragraph can also contain
			_metadata_
			as key-value pairs, also referred to as the
			_commit message footer_
			.


			This metadata can be used to trigger a certain
			behavior. For
			example the
			_Gerrit_
			code review system uses the
			<parameter>Change-Id</parameter>
			key followed by a
			_change-id_
			, which does not change across different versions of the same code
			review. This
			_changed id_
			is used to identify to which review the message
			belongs.
		
		
			The
			_commit message footer_
			can also have e.g., 'Signed-off-by' and may be used to
			link to a bug
			tracking system, e.g., 'Bug: 1234'.
		
	
[[commitmessages_repo">
=== Example message
		The following can serve as an example for a commit message.
		
		
			<programlisting language="text">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/message/message.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		

	
[[commitmessages_history">
=== Good and bad example for a Git history

		
			The following listing shows the output of the
			<code>git log --oneline</code>
			command of a Git repository
			with
			bad commit messages. The first value
			in each line
			is the shortened SHA-1, the second the commit message.
			This history
			is
			not useful.
		
		
			<programlisting language="text">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/message/bad.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		


		The next listing shows the history of another Git repository
			in
			which better commit messages have been used. This history already
			gives
			a good overview about the activities.
		

		
			<programlisting language="text">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/message/good.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		
		The above example also adds the corresponding bug number to the
			commit message. Some teams (like the Eclipse platform team) use this
			approach, others prefer to add
			the bug number to the commit messages.
		

	



