== Defining a target platform
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Target platform</primary>
		<secondary>Definition</secondary>
	</indexterm>

		
			You can specify your target platform with a
			_target definition file_
			. With such a file you define the available plug-ins and features.
		
		TIP:
			A target platform can be defined based on software sites (p2 update sites) or
				other means. As build systems like
				Maven Tycho support only p2 update sites,
				it is recommended to use only these.
			
		
	
		A target definition file can be created via
		menu:
			<guimenu>File</guimenu>
			<guisubmenu>New</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Other...</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Plug-in Development</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Target Definition</guisubmenu>
		</menuchoice>
		.
	
	
image::targetdefinition10.png[]
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Define File name for Target Definition</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	
	
		You can add new locations via the
		_Add..._
		button in the Locations
		section. To add an Eclipse p2 update site,
		select
		_Software Site_
		and
		specify the URL.
	

	
		Once you have a target definition file, you can set
		it as
		the
		target platform in your Eclipse IDE. This can be done via
		the
		_Set as Target Platform_
		link in the Target definition editor as depicted in the following
		screenshot.
	
	
image::targetdefinition20.png[]
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Setting the new defined target definition as target for
					the
					development</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	
	TIP:
		Wait until the target platform is completely resolved before setting it as target platform.
	
	
	
		All plug-ins you are planning to use in your application and test code must be included in the target definition. For example, if you want, for example, use SWTBot for unit tests, add
		_SWTBot for SWT Testing_ features
		from
		http://download.eclipse.org/technology/swtbot/releases/latest/
		to
		your
		target platform.
    
	
image::tutorial_targetdefinition50.png[]
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Definition of a target definition file</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	
			
	
	
		You can switch the target platform in the Eclipse Preferences.
		Select
		menu:
			<guimenu>Window</guimenu>
			<guisubmenu>Preferences</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Plug-in Development</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Target Platform</guisubmenu>
		</menuchoice>
		.
	
	
image::targetdefinition30.png[]
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Setting the target definition via the Eclipse Preferences</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	

	
		The most effective
		way of
		defining
		your
		target platform
		is to
		use p2
		update
		sites. These are of the same type as
		the
		update
		sites
		that you used
		to
		install a new set of plug-ins. If
		the
		content in the
		update sites
		defined by your target
		platform
		changes,
		your local set of
		plug-ins
		can
		be updated.
	
	
		It is also possible to define your target platform based on
		plug-ins
		in your
		file system, but this is not
		recommended as certain
		build system like Maven/Tycho do not support file based target
		definition files.
	


