== API definition of a plug-in

	<indexterm>
		<primary>OSGi</primary>
		<secondary>provisional API</secondary>
	</indexterm>



	
		In the
		_MANIFEST.MF_
		file a plug-in also defines its API via the Export-Package
		Identifier.
		All packages which are not explicitly exported
		are not
		visible to
		other
		plug-ins.
	

	
image::osgi_api_definition10.png" />
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Dependency management</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	

	
		All these restrictions are enforced via a
		specific
		OSGi
		`classloader`
		. Each plug-in has its own classloader. Access to
		restricted classes
		is
		not
		possible.
	
	Unfortunately OSGi can not prevent you from using Java
		reflection to access these classes. This is because OSGi
		is
		based on
		the Java runtime which does not yet support a modularity layer.
	



	
		Via the
		`x-internal`
		flag the OSGi runtime can mark an exported package as provisional.
		This allows other plug-ins to consume the
		corresponding classes, but indicates that these classes
		are not considered as official API.
	
	
		The following screenshot shows how to set a package as
		`x-internal`
		in the
		manifest editor.
	

	
image::x-internal10.png" />
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Setting the x-internal flag</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	

	 This is how the corresponding manifest file looks like.

	
		<programlisting language="bourne">
			<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" parse="text" href="./examples/snippets/mani.txt[]
----
	

	
		You can configure how the Eclipse Java editor shows the usage of
		provisional API. Such an access can be
		configured
		to
		be displayed as, error, warning
		or if such access should be result in no additional message.
	
	
		The
		default
		is to display
		a warning message. You
		can adjust
		this in
		the
		Eclipse
		preferences via
		the
		menu:
			<guimenu>Window</guimenu>
			<guisubmenu>Preferences</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Java</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Compiler</guisubmenu>
			<guisubmenu>Errors/Warnings</guisubmenu>
		</menuchoice>
		preference setting.
	


	
image::x-internal30.png" />
			
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Settings in Eclipse for warnings for deprecated API usage</phrase>
			</textobject>
		
	

	
		You can define that a set of plug-ins can access
		provisional API
		without a warning or error message. This can be done
		via the
		`x-friends`
		directive. This flag is added if you add a plug-in to
		the
		_Package Visibility_
		section on the
		_Runtime_
		tab of the
		manifest editor.
	

	
		<programlisting language="common">
			<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" parse="text" href="./examples/snippets/friends.txt[]
----
	
	
		The
		`x-friends`
		setting has the same effect as
		`x-internal`
		but all plug-ins mentioned in the x-friends setting can access the
		package without receiving an error or warning
		message.
	


