
== Local deployment of your plug-in

=== Options for installing a plug-in
		

		

		
			You have several options to make your plug-in available in your
			Eclipse IDE. You can:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					Install your plug-in directly into your current Eclipse installation, using your Eclipse IDE. This
						option is
						useful for
						a quick
						installation and a test during development.
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					
						Export your plug-in and copy it into the
						_dropins_
						folder of your Eclipse installation. This option is useful for a simple distribution scenario,
						where you only have
						to
						provide the exported plug-in to
						your users. On
						the other hand it is not very convenient for the end user as it
						requires manual file copying and
						provides no simple way to update
						the plug-in.
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					
						Create an update site and use the Eclipse update manager
						to
						install it from this site. This is the simplest
						approach for the end user. It also allows providing updates to all interested users.
					
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
	


=== Installing your plug-in from your Eclipse IDE

		
			You can install
			your plug-in directly into your running Eclipse
			IDE.
		
		
			The Eclipse plug-in export wizard has an option for this. Open the
			export wizard via
			menu:File[Export > Plug-in Development > Deployable plug-ins and fragments]
			.
		
		
image::eclipseideexport10.png[Export plug-in into host IDE,pdfwidth=60%]
		
		
			In the export wizard
			dialog select in this case
			_Install into host. Repository_
			. This is depicted in the following screenshot.
		

		
image::eclipseideexport20.png[Export plug-in into host IDE,pdfwidth=60%]
		

	


		
=== Export plug-in and put into dropins folder
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Plug-in deployment</primary>
			<secondary>
				export and installation into dropins folder
			</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		
			If you export your plug-in locally, you can put it into the
			Eclipse
			<filename class="directory">dropins_
			folder of your Eclipse installation. After a restart
			of your Eclipse
			your plug-in should be available and ready for
			use.
		

		
			Open again the
			export wizard via
			menu:File[Export > Plug-in Development > Deployable plug-ins and fragments]
			.
		


		
			Select the plug-in you want to export and the folder to which
			this plug-in should get exported.
		
		
image::eclipseideexport30.png"/>

				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Export plug-in into host IDE,pdfwidth=60%]
		

		
			Press the
			_Finish_
			button.
			This creates a
			_JAR_
			file with the exported plug-in in the selected directory.
		

		
			Copy this
			_JAR_
			file
			to
			the
			<filename class="directory">dropins_
			directory in your Eclipse installation directory and
			restart your
			running Eclipse.
		
		
			After this restart your new plug-in is available
			in
			your
			Eclipse
			installation and ready to be used.
		

	


=== Deployment using an update site
		
		
		
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Plug-in deployment</primary>
			<secondary>
				Using update sites
			</secondary>
		</indexterm>

		
			You can create an update site for your plug-in. An update
			site
			consists of static files, which can be placed on a
			file server or
			a
			web
			server. Other users can install Eclipse plug-in from this update
			site
			by providing them a link to the
			update site.
		

		
			This
			requires that you create a
			feature project for the plug-in.
			You can
			export this feature project and use the
			Eclipse update manager
			to
			install the
			feature (with the plug-in).
		

		
			By
			default, the
			Eclipse update manager shows
			only features
			included into a
			category. Therefore, you
			should always
			use a
			category for your
			exported
			feature to make it
			easy for the user to install your feature.
		
	
