<preface role="preface">
	<title>Foreword</title>    <para>
        The Eclipse platform is one of the world's most successful open
        source software projects. Millions of developers use Eclipse every day
        as their tooling platform. Millions of users every day use
        applications built on top of the Eclipse Rich Client Platform. The
        primary motivation of our community's newest major release - Eclipse 4
        - is to make Eclipse an even better platform, particularly a better
        application platform. The Eclipse team has been working on this major
        revision for over six years, and Eclipse 4 has been the underlying
        platform for the Eclipse simultaneous releases since the Juno release
        in June of 2012. We are all excited to see this major new innovation
        launching into the mainstream of enterprise development.
    </para>
    <para>
        One of the keys to Eclipse's success is the commitment of the
        development team to platform stability, and release-to-release
        compatibility. This requires remarkable effort and discipline on their
        part, but has made Eclipse a stable foundation on which to build.
        Eclipse 4 will make it even easier for Java developers to build and
        deploy great-looking and portable desktop applications, by bringing a
        simpler, yet more powerful, set of APIs for application developers to
        use.
    </para>
    <para>
        Eclipse projects are driven by great developers, and the Eclipse
        4 project
        has had many important contributors. I would like to
        recognize the
        contributions of just a few: the present Eclipse platform
        leader Mike
        Wilson, and project leaders Dani Megert, John Arthorne, all
        from IBM
        and Boris Bokowski, originally with IBM but now with Google. I
        would
        also like to recognize the special contributions to Eclipse 4 of
        Brian   de Alwis, 
        Oleg Besedin, 
        Danail Branekov, 
        Dirk Fauth, 
        Bogdan Gheorghe, 
        Noopur Gupta, 
        Markus Keller, 
        Alexander Kurtakov, 
        Andrey Loskutov, 
        Eric Moffatt, 
        Sergey Prigogin, 
        Thomas Schindl, 
        Simon Scholz, 
        Remy Suen, 
        Kai Tödter, 
        Paul Webster, 
        Tomas Zama, 
        and, of course, your author Lars Vogel. Finally, it bears mentioning that the
        Eclipse 4 platform would not exist without the continuing investment
        and resource commitments of IBM, BestSolution.at, and SAP.
    </para>
    <para>
        Lars Vogel has been contributing to the Eclipse 4 project almost since its
        inception, and has recently been recognized by the community by becoming the 
        co-leader of the Platform UI and e4 projects.
        For many years, he has also been one of the most visible
        evangelists for Eclipse in general, and for Eclipse 4 in particular.
        In short, he is one of the leading experts in using Eclipse 4 for
        building applications. This book provides developers with the
        information they need to be successful with this exciting new Eclipse
        platform version. I am sure that you will find it an excellent
        addition to your Eclipse library.
    </para>

    <para>
        <literallayout>
            Mike Milinkovich
            Executive Director, Eclipse Foundation
        </literallayout>
    </para>
</preface>