<chapter id="tutorial_i22n">
== Optional Exercise: Internationalization for the application model


=== Target
		In this exercise you translate the relevant parts of your
			application model and use the translation service.
		
	


=== Create the translations for the application model
		
			Create the
			_OSGI-INF/l10n_
			folder in your
			`com.example.e4.rcp.todo`
			plug-in.
		
		
			Create the
			_bundle.properties_
			file with key/values for the parts in your application model in this
			folder. The file might look like the following.
		
		
[source,java]
----
include::res/i18n/bundle.properties[]
----
		
		
			Create at least one additional translation file for another language. For example, if English is your default
			language,
			create the
			_bundle_de.properties_
			file to provide a German translation. Ensure that the translation values are different.
		
	



=== Adjust the build.properties file
		
			Add the created property files to your build.properties file in the
			`com.example.e4.rcp.todo`
			plug-in to make
			it available in an exported application.
		
	


=== Translate the application model
		Use the defined keys with the % prefix in your application
			model. The following screenshot demonstrates that for
			a part.
		
		
image::exercise_appmodel_translation10.png[Using the translation keys in the application model,pdfwidth=60%]
		


	


=== Test the translation of the application model
		

			Ensure that the
			application works well for the languages you provided translations for. You can set the language in
			your
			launch
			configuration by
			using the
			<parameter class="option">-nl_
			start parameter as described in
			<xref linkend="i18n_nlparameter" />
		
		<warning>
			
				You have to change the launch configuration. Setting the language via the product file does not work, as the nl
				parameter is
				currently
				not
				correctly transferred to the launch configuration. See
				https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=461371">PDE Bug report
				for details.
			
		
	

=== Application model and translations
		
			By default, it is not possible to define that the translations for the
			application model
			are located in another
			plug-in. If you want
			this, you have to implement
			your custom translation service.
		

	
</chapter>
	
	
