== Common product export problems

=== Problems with the export and log files
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Log file</primary>
			<secondary>Exported RCP application</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		
			During the export or the start of the exported application you may
			encounter
			problems. If your application got successfully exported but
			cannot be started you find
			a log file
			ending with the
			_.log_
			extension in the
			_configuration_
			folder of your application. This file contains the error you
			encountered.
		
		Alternatively the export process may fail. In both cases you can
			use
			this chapter as reference to try to find and fix the reason for
			the failure.
		
	

		<indexterm>
			<primary>Deployment</primary>
			<secondary>Common problems</secondary>
		</indexterm>
=== Export problem number #1: export folder is not empty
		
			The most common problem is that the folder to which you export
			is not
			empty.
			If you export to a certain folder, ensure that the
			folder
			is empty. Exporting twice to the same folder may create file locks
			or
			results in error messages reporting version conflicts.
		
	

=== Checklist for common export problems
		
			If the export encounters a problem please have a look into the
			following table
			for a solution:

.Table Title
|===

		=== Problems with the product export
				<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' colwidth="1*>>
					<colspec colname='c2' colwidth="2*>>
					
						
|Problem
|Possible cause
						
					
					
						
|Export fails
|Try using an empty target directory, sometimes
								the export
								cannot delete the existing files and therefore fails.
							
						
						
|No executable file after the export
|
								Check the flag "The product
								includes native
								launcher
								artifacts" in
								your .product file on the
								_Overview_
								tab.
							
						
						
|Product could not be found
|Validate that all dependencies
								are included in the product.
								Delete an existing launch
								configuration and restart the product
								from the IDE to see if
								everything is configured correctly.
							
						
						
|Splash screen or other icons are missing
|
								Check the
								_build.properties_
								file to see if all required images and
								icons are
								included in
								the
								export.
							
						
						
|Splash screen is missing
|Ensure that you have entered the defining plug-in in the
								"Splash" tab on the product configuration file. If this is not
								set, the splash screen is not displayed after the export.
								Unfortunately, it is displayed if you start the plug-in
								from the
								Eclipse IDE.
							
						
						
|Issues during start of the application
|Check the log file in the
								workspace folder of your exported
								application to see the error messages
								during the start process.
								Alternatively
								add the
								"-consoleLog" parameter to the ".ini" file
								in folder
								of
								the
								exported application.
							
						
						
|applicationXMI argument is missing
|
								Check the
								_build.properties_
								file to see if the
								_Application.e4xmi_
								and
								the
								_plugin.xml_
								files are
								included in
								the export.
							
						
						
|Service could not be found or injected
|
								Make sure that the bundle which provides the service has the
								_Activate this plug-in when one of its classes is
									loaded
								_
								flag set. Also
								make
								sure
								that the
								`org.eclipse.equinox.ds`
								bundle
								is started automatically with a
								_Start Level_
								less than 4.
							
						
						
|Application ID could not be found
|
								Define a
								start
								level of 1 and set auto-start to true for the
								`org.eclipse.core.runtime`
								plug-in.
							
						
						
|Translations not available in the exported product
|
								Ensure via the
								_build.properties_
								file of the relevant plug-in that the files containing the
								translations are included in
								the export.
							
						


					
				
|===

		
	
